# **Manel Bouguerra**

**E-mail:** manel01bouguerra@gmail.com

**Tel:** +21653129965

Address: Agareb 3030, Sfax, Tunisia.

**LinkedIn:** <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/manel-bouguerra-2234236b/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/manel-bouguerra-2234236b/</a> **ResearchGate:** <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Manel-Bouguerra">https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Manel-Bouguerra</a>



# Doctor of Philosophy in Chemistry - Scientific researcher - Laboratory Technician - Post-Doctoral Fellowship - Inorganic Chemistry - Solid State Chemistry

Enthusiastic, dynamic and adaptive Senior researcher in Materials chemistry with the ability and willingness to learn, commit and grow among an ambitious interdisciplinary team.

#### Summary of skills

- Inorganic chemistry
- Hybrid/Inorganic and organic synthesis
- Marketing and negotiation

- Materials characterizations
- Quality control and production management
- Mentoring and supervising

#### Skills related to the position

#### **Technical**

- Schlenk Line and Cannulation Techniques.
- Spectroscopic IR/Raman measurements.
- DSC/TGA/DTA.
- UV-Vis, Fluorescence.

IT Excellent computer skills. Competent in Microsoft Office, ChemDraw, OriginLab, Crystal Explorer, Mercury, Diamond Software, MasterNova ...

#### Languages:

- Arabic (Mother Tongue)
- English (Professional)
- French (Professional)

- German (Conversational)
- Italian (Beginner)

#### Management Different management skills applied

- Research and development.
- Organization and punctuality
- Determination

- Engagement and Motivation
- Analytical skills and problem solving
- Oriented thinking in group work processes.

### Professional Experience

• Doctoral researcher

(01/01/2017 - 31/12/2021)

Laboratory of Physico-chemistry of solid-state, Sfax, Tunisia.

Crystal engineering, physico-chemical characterizations and biological activities of some metal-organic halides.

• Visiting Researcher

(01/10/2020 - 01/02/2021)

Institute of Inorganic and Analytical Chemistry, Mainz, Germany.

Organometallics, coordination chemistry, organometallic synthesis, magnetic properties.

• Visiting Researcher

(15/03/2019 - 30/07/2019)

Laboratory of Organometallics synthesis, Cluj-Napoca, Romania.

Synthesis and characterization of organometallic substances under a controlled atmosphere.

• Data collector and team assistant

(01/03/2018 - 30/06/2018)

IDEA CONSULT, Sfax, Tunisia.

Collecting data about the national project "Metro of Sfax". Treatment of the obtained results and managing the relevant files and obtained data.

Group leader

(01/12/2014 - 30/09/2015)

## CLUBSHOP REWARDS, Worldwide

Online sale and marketing of different services. Starting first with market investigation and identification of customer needs, implantation in the market and negotiating selling strategies.

• Trainee

(01/03/2015 - 01/05/2015)

Laboratory of Materials Science and Environment, Faculty of Sciences of Sfax, Tunisia Bioactive Fluorosilicated glasses as bones filling (Verres Bioactifs Fluorosilicatés en tant que biomatériaux de comblement osseux).

• Trainee

(01/06/2014 - 01/07/2014)

SCHLUMBERGER DOWELL, Sfax, Tunisia.

Main task of petroleum laboratory chemist. QHSE training.

#### Education

• Ph.D IN INORGANIC CHEMISTRY

University of Sfax- TN (2018 -2021)

• MASTER OF INORGANIC CHEMISTRY

University of Sfax- TN (2015-2017)

• LICENCE OF CHEMISTRY

University of Sfax-TN (2012 - 2015)

#### Achievements

- **Publication of a paper** entitled: Physico-chemical study of new supramolecular- architectured hybrid organic—inorganic sulfates incorporating diammonium diphenylsulfone cations [2021].
- Oral communication: 2021 The 2<sup>nd</sup> International Meeting on Advanced Materials (IMAM-2021) "Synthesis, crystal structure, vibrational spectroscopy, thermal study and Visible Absorption of a new hybrid compound containing chlorate anions of stannate (II)".
- Oral communication: 2021 35th Eg-MRS international conference "Structural study, thermal analysis, vibrational and optical properties of a novel organic inorganic hybrid perovskite".
- Oral communication: 2018 Tunisia Chemistry Conference hosted by the Tunisian Chemical Society-"Synthesis and characterization of two organic-inorganic salts: sulfates of diphenyl sulfone derivatives."
- **Poster**: 2021 The 2<sup>nd</sup> International Meeting on Advanced Materials (IMAM-2021) "Novel lead-free hybrid perovskite-like compound investigation: Synthesis, Crystal Structure, Thermal Stability and UV-Vis Absorption.".
- **Poster**: 2017 The 8<sup>th</sup> International Conference in Solid State Chemistry "Chemical synthesis, crystal structure, thermal analysis, vibrational and uv-vis spectroscopy of new hybrid compound based on sulfate."

Having attended

- World Youth Forum. Sharm El Sheikh, Egypt January 2022.
- International School on Sensors for Body Area Networks. Online 31st May- 4th June 2021.
- Health and Security in Laboratories. Faculty of Sciences of Sfax 24th January 2019.
- **Bio-Polymers.** University of Sfax 1st and 2nd March 2019.
- Euro-Mediterranean Intercultural Trends. Online December 2019.
- Various Coursera courses.